class Science {
  static const List<Map<String, dynamic>> thirdPeriodical =
      <Map<String, dynamic>>[
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'terrestrial ecosystems',
      'question':
          'are determined by the presence or type of land, climate, humidity, and temperature.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'aquatic ecosystems',
      'question':
          'are determined by the presence of water, depth, flow, and temperature.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'freshwater ecosystem',
      'question':
          'includes flowing water like rivers and streams, and standing water like lakes and ponds.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'estuaries',
      'question': 'are ecosystems where fresh and saltwater meet.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'marine ecosystem',
      'question': 'includes the ocean and sea that has salty water.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'abiotic factors',
      'question':
          'non-living factors that provide shape and support to the ecosystem.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'biotic factors',
      'question': 'are all living things within the ecosystem.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'resources',
      'question':
          'pertain to anything that is essential for the survival of living things.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'renewable resources',
      'question':
          'can regenerate or recycle naturally and are therefore replaceable.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'nonrenewable',
      'question':
          'are those that cannot be replenished by natural processes or in an instant.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'land',
      'question':
          'is significant to the survival of all living things because it is the basic component of all ecosystems.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'land',
      'question':
          'it serves as an anchorage for plants that bear nutrients and serves as a habitat for small animals',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'water',
      'question':
          "seventy percent of the earth is composed of this and can be considered as the Earth's blood.",
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'water',
      'question': 'it serves as a habitat for aquatic organisms.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'air',
      'question': 'it is the breath of the earth.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'air',
      'question': 'it is a mixture of gases like oxygen and carbon dioxide.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'light',
      'question':
          "fuels the plant's process of photosynthesis to make its own food.",
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'light',
      'question':
          'its main source is the sun which provides energy to plants and vitamins for animals.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'temperature',
      'question': 'is the measure of hotness and coldness.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'producers',
      'question':
          'are living things that depend on the energy coming from the sun and inorganic compounds like water and carbon dioxide that allows them to produce their own food and do not depend on other organisms to survive.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'autotrophs',
      'question': "this means 'self-feeders.'",
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'consumers',
      'question': "comes from the word consume which means 'eaters.'",
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'herbivores',
      'question': 'exclusively plant eaters.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'carnivores',
      'question': 'exclusively eat other animals for its meat.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'omnivores',
      'question': 'eat both plants and animals.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'decomposers',
      'question':
          'are also known as transformers because they break down organic materials present in decaying organisms.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'symbiosis',
      'question': 'the close interaction between two organisms.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'competition',
      'question':
          'organisms that fight to gain resources important for their survival.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'competition',
      'question':
          'an organism of the same or different species compete for certain resources.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'predator',
      'question': 'it is the organism that hunts another organism for food.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'prey',
      'question': 'it is the organism eaten by another organism.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'mutualism',
      'question':
          'is the interaction where both organisms benefit from each other.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'commensalism',
      'question':
          'one of the organisms benefits while the other is neither benefited nor harmed.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'parasitism',
      'question':
          "one of the organisms lives within the other organism and sometimes causes the host's death.",
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'habitat',
      'question': 'is the place where organisms live.',
    },
  ];

  static const List<Map<String, dynamic>> thirdMonthly = <Map<String, dynamic>>[
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'reproduction',
      'question': 'the means of all organisms to make new organisms.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'gametes',
      'question':
          'reproductive cells that contain half the number of chromosomes.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'chromosomes',
      'question':
          'carry the information that decides how the organisms will look a like.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'chromosomes',
      'question': 'the nuclei of the two cells, together with this, unite.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'genes',
      'question':
          'provide the instructions and control the manifestation of traits.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'fertilization',
      'question': 'the union of male and female.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'fertilization',
      'question': 'is possible when a male gamete meets with a female gamete.',
    },
    <String, String>{'answer': 'egg', 'question': 'female gamete'},
    <String, String>{'answer': 'sperm', 'question': 'male gamete'},
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'zygote',
      'question': 'results when two cells unite.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'internal fertilization',
      'question': 'occurs within the reproductive system.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'penis',
      'question': 'responsible for the transfer of sperm cells.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'copulation',
      'question':
          'the transfer of male gamete into the female reproductive system.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'external fertilization',
      'question': 'occurs in the outside environment.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'sex organs',
      'question': 'responsible for the formation of gametes.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'dioecious',
      'question': 'organisms that may either be male or female.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'monoecious or hermaphroditic',
      'question': 'means two houses in the Greek word.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'monoecious or hermaphroditic',
      'question':
          'organisms that have both male and female reproductive systems.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'protogyny',
      'question': 'the ability to switch or change sex.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'protandry',
      'question': 'when the sperms are produced before the egg.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'protogyny',
      'question': 'when the egg cells are produced before the sperm cells.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'stamen',
      'question': 'the male part of the flower.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'stamen',
      'question': 'the reproductive structure in the plants.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'carpel',
      'question': 'the female part of the flower.',
    },
    <String, String>{'answer': 'pollen', 'question': 'the male gametophyte.'},
    <String, String>{'answer': 'ovule', 'question': 'the female gametophyte.'},
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'fallopian tube',
      'question':
          'female reproductive system organ where the union of the egg and sperm occurs.',
    },
    <String, String>{
      'answer': 'sperm cell',
      'question': 'penetrates once the sperm cells reach the matured egg.',
    }
  ];
}
